双语特效字幕
“龙堡字幕组”携手“衣柜字幕组”诚挚奉献
专注GOT剧集 华语冰火最专业字幕
翻译   红毒蛇奥柏伦
翻译   北落师门
狭海  The Narrow Sea
君临 King's Landing
翻译   Violet_Rosa
红堡
Red Keep
翻译  龙的命根子
校对  suerhine
鹰    巢    城     The     Eyrie
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
鹰
The
巢
Eyrie
鹰
The
城
Eyrie
巢
城
鹰
巢
城
The
Eyrie
咬人湾  The Bite
校对   临冬城的狮子
临冬城 Winterfell
复校   托曼
人人网冰与火之歌公共主页
http://page.renren.com/601227719/index
后期  poplar
压制  麻绳力攻
绝境长城 the Wall
策划   baozhenyuawabi
协助   空格
最专业的华语冰火资料站：冰与火之歌中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
龙堡字幕组 & 百度冰与火之歌贴吧 & 百度权力的游戏贴吧   联合出品
维斯·多斯拉克
Vaes·Dothrak
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
特
别
顾
问
：
屈畅
(ccxx)
特
别
顾
问
：
屈畅
(ccxx)
权力的游戏
第一季 第八集
龙堡字幕组 & 衣柜字幕组
第八集  “剑之尖端”
"The Pointy End"
呀！左上！左下！
Yah! Left high, left low.
右下！右突刺！
Right low, lunge right.
你打碎一件东西 修女就会要我的脑袋
You break anything, the Septa will have my head.
发生什么…
What is--
你妹妹明明知道我们今天要走
Your sister knew perfectly well we were to leave today.
- 她怎么能忘了 - 她没忘
- How she could forget - She didn't forget.
她和她的舞蹈老师在一起 每个早上都是这样
She's with her dancing master. She's with him every morning.
然后带着擦伤和淤青回来 她总是这么鲁莽
She always comes back with scrapes and bruises. She's so clumsy.
茉丹
临冬城的修女
嘘！
Hush!
快回房间
Go back to your room.
珊莎·史塔克
临冬城公爵长女
把门堵上
Bar the doors
别为任何陌生人开门
and do not open them for anyone you do not know.
- 怎么了？发生了什么？ - 按我说的做
- What is it? What's happening? - Do as I told you.
快跑！
Run!
这里！
This way!
左！右！啊！
Left, right. Rah!
你已经死了
Now you are dead.
艾莉亚·史塔克
临冬城公爵次女
你说的是右
You said right,
但却往左刺
but you went left.
没错 然后你就是个死女孩了
And now you are a dead girl.
只是因为你骗人
Only 'cause you lied.
我的舌头说了谎 但我的眼睛
My tongue lied. My eyes
西利欧·佛瑞尔
布拉佛斯剑术家
说的却是事实 可你视而不见
shouted the truth.You were not seeing.
我有 我看了 但你…
I was so. I watched, but you--
死掉的丫头 观看并不代表洞察
Watching is not seeing, dead girl.
洞察 真正的洞察
The seeing, the true seeing,
才是剑术的灵魂
that is the heart of swordplay.
艾丽娅·史塔克 跟我们来
Arya Stark, come with us.
你父亲要见你
Your father wants to see you.
我很好奇
And why is it
为什么艾德不派自己的人
that Lord Eddard is sending Lannister men
却派来了几个兰尼斯特的人？
in place of his own? I am wondering.
舞蹈老师 别不识好歹
Mind your place, dancing master.
此事跟你毫无干系
This is no concern of yours.
你们不是我父亲派来的
My father wouldn't send you.
而且只要我不乐意 就不会跟你们走
And I don't have to go with you if I don't want.
马林·特兰
御林铁卫
带走她
Take her.
竟然威胁一个孩子 你们是人还是禽兽？
Are you men or snakes, that you would threaten a child?
滚开 小个子
Get out of my way, little man.
我乃西利欧·佛瑞尔…
I am Syrio Forel...
卷毛杂种
Foreign bastard.
…你们跟我说话的时候要更有礼貌
...And you will be speaking to me with more respect.
干掉这个布拉佛斯人 抓住那丫头
Kill the Braavosi. Bring the girl.
小艾丽娅 今天的舞蹈课就到此为止
Arya child, we are done with dancing for the day.
快去找你的父亲
Run to your father.
他妈的一群蠢货
Bloody oafs.
快走 艾丽娅
Be gone now, Arya.
跟我走 一起走
Come with me. Run.
布拉佛斯的首席剑士从不临阵脱逃
The First Sword of Braavos does not run.
我们是
What do we say
怎么回答死神的？
to the God of Death?
时候未到
Not today.
快走
Go.
时候未到 时候未到
Not today. Not today.
离我远点
Stay away from me.
我要告诉我的父亲
I'll tell my father.
我要…我要告诉王后
I'll-- I'll tell the Queen.
你以为是谁派我来的？
Who do you think sent me?
缝衣针
Needle.
她在那儿
There she is.
- 你要干什么？ - 我要你 小狼女
- What do you want? - I want you, wolf girl.
- 过来 - 别过来！
- Come here. - Leave me be.
我的父亲是公爵 他会重赏你的
My father's a lord. He'll reward you.
王后那儿才真有重赏
She'll reward me-- the Queen!
滚开！
Stay away!
史塔克大人 你一定很渴
Lord Stark, you must be thirsty.
艾德·史塔克
临冬城公爵 昵称“奈德”
瓦里斯
Varys.
我向你保证这不是毒酒
I promise you it isn't poisoned.
为什么就没人相信一次太监呢？
Why is it no one ever trusts the eunuch?
大人 别一次喝这么多
Not so much, My Lord.
如果我是你 就会把剩下的好好保存起来
I would save the rest, if I were you.
藏起来吧 这些牢里可是渴死过人的
Hide it. Men have been known to die of thirst in these cells.
我女儿们怎样了？
What about my daughters?
小的那个似乎逃出了城堡
The younger one seems to have escaped the castle.
连我的小小鸟都不知道她的踪迹
Even my little birds cannot find her.
- 珊莎呢？ - 她还是乔佛里的未婚妻
- And Sansa? - Still engaged to Joffrey.
瑟曦把她留在了身边 而您那些手下
Cersei will keep her close. The rest of your household though--
都死掉啦 说起来真难过啊
all dead, it grieves me to say.
我真讨厌看见血
I do so hate the sight of blood.
我的人被屠杀 而你只是袖手旁观
You watched my men being slaughtered and did nothing.
瓦里斯
太监 情报总管 “八爪蜘蛛”
再来一次我依然会那么做 大人
And would again, My Lord.
我手无寸铁 身无片甲 又被兰尼斯特的精兵环绕
I was unarmed, unarmored and surrounded by Lannister swords.
我看起来很像英雄吗？
When you look at me do you see a hero?
你是发了什么疯才会告诉王后
What madness led you to tell the Queen
你知道乔佛里身世的真相？
you had learned the truth about Joffrey's birth?
仁慈的疯狂
The madness of mercy.
让她有机会拯救她的孩子们
That she might save her children.
啊 孩子们
Ah, the children.
总是无辜的人受罪
It is always the innocents who suffer.
杀死劳勃的并不是酒 也不是野猪
It wasn't the wine that killed Robert, nor the boar.
美酒只是让他行动缓慢 野猪不过将他身体撕裂
The wine slowed him down and the boar ripped him open,
真正杀死国王的 乃是你所谓的仁慈
but it was your mercy that killed the King.
我想你已经知道自己难逃一死了吧 艾德大人？
I trust you know you are a dead man, Lord Eddard?
王后不能杀我
The Queen can't kill me.
她的兄弟还在凯特手上
Cat holds her brother.
真可惜 此兄弟非彼兄弟
The wrong brother sadly.
而且他也逃掉了
And lost to her.
你的妻子让小恶魔从手指缝里溜走了
Your wife has let the Imp slip through her fingers.
果真如此的话
If that's true,
帮我做个了结 割了我的喉咙
then slit my throat and be done with it.
时候未到 大人
Not today, My Lord.
告诉我 瓦里斯
Tell me something, Varys.
你效忠的究竟是谁
Who do you truly serve?
回大人 是这个国家
The Realm, My Lord.
总得有人这么做
Someone must.
这是奥瑟 错不了
It's Othor, without a doubt.
另一个是杰佛·佛花 大人
The other one is Jafer Flowers, My Lord,
少了一只手 被狼叼走的那只
less the hand the wolf tore off.
有班扬或者他手下其他人的踪迹么
Any sign of Benjen or the rest of his party?
就这两个 大人
Just these two, My Lord.
我得说 他们死了有一会儿了
Been dead awhile, I'd say.
这味道
The smell.
波文·马尔锡
守夜人的首席事务官
什么味道
What smell?
山姆威尔·塔利
守夜人事务官
什么味道也没有
There is none.
如果他们已经死了很长时间了 尸体为什么不腐烂？
If they'd be dead for a long time, wouldn't there be rot?
我们应该把尸体火化
We should burn them.
雪诺说的不错 大人 应该火化
Snow's not wrong, My Lord. Fire will do for them.
那是野人的方式
The wildling way.
杰奥·莫尔蒙
守夜人总司令
我想先让伊蒙师傅检查一下
I want Maester Aemon to examine them first.
塔利 你可能是个懦夫
You may be a coward, Tarly,
不过绝对不蠢
but you're not stupid.
- 抬进去 - 快照办
- Get them inside. - You heard him.
总司令大人
Lord Commander,
伊蒙师傅在他的房间里等你
Maester Aemon awaits you in his chambers
有来自君临的乌鸦
A raven from King's Landing.
快 抬出去
Come on, move 'em out.
给我来一杯麦芽酒 雪诺
Bring me a horn of ale, Snow,
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人总司令的事务官
给你自己也来一杯
and pour one for yourself.
国王死了
The King is dead.
有我父亲的消息吗？
Is there any word of my father?
坐下
Sit.
史塔克现在
Lord Stark has been
被控犯下叛国罪行
charged with treason.
他们说他跟劳勃的兄弟们密谋
They say he conspired with Robert's brothers
篡夺乔佛里王子的王位
to deny the throne to Prince Joffrey.
我希望你不要想着去做什么傻事
I hope you're not thinking of doing anything stupid.
因为现在你的职责在这里
Your duty lies here now.
我的妹妹们也在君临
My sisters were in King's Landing too.
我确定
I'm sure they'll be
他们会礼待你的妹妹们
treated gently.
亲爱的 你父亲犯下了可耻的叛国罪行
Your father has proved to be an awful traitor, dear.
劳勃国王尸骨未寒
King Robert's body was still warm
他就在密谋夺取乔佛里的王位
when Lord Eddard began plotting to steal Joffrey's rightful throne.
他不会那么做的
He wouldn't do that.
他知道我有多爱乔佛里 他不会的
He knows how much I love Joffrey. He wouldn't.
求求你了 陛下 这一定是个误会
Please, Your Grace, there's been a mistake.
传召我的父亲啊 他会告诉你…国王是他的朋友啊
Send for my father. He'll tell you-- the King was his friend.
亲爱的珊莎 你是无辜的 我们知道
Sansa sweetling, you are innocent of any wrong. We know that.
但你是叛国者的女儿
Yet you are the daughter of a traitor.
我怎能再让你嫁给我的儿子？
How can I allow you to marry my son?
你是叛国者的种
A child born of a traitor's seed
不适合做国王的配偶
is no fit consort for our King.
陛下 她现在还是个小甜心
She is a sweet thing now, Your Grace,
但是又有谁知道十年之后
but in 10 years who knows
她会犯下怎样的罪行？
what treasons she may hatch?
不 我不会的 我会是他的好妻子 你们会看到的
No, I'm not. I'll be a good wife to him, you'll see.
我保证会像您那样做个好王后的 我不会干任何坏事的
I'll be a Queen just like you, I promise. I won't hatch anything.
陛下 这女孩是无辜的
The girl is innocent, Your Grace.
应该给她一个机会去让她证明忠心
She should be given a chance to prove her loyalty.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
摄政太后
小鸽子 你必须给凯特琳夫人写封信
Little dove, you must write to Lady Catelyn
还有你的长兄 他叫什么？
and your brother, the eldest, what's his name?
罗柏
Robb.
毫无疑问 他很快就会得知你父亲被捕的消息
Word of your father's arrest will reach him soon, no doubt.
那么最好由你来告诉他
Best it comes from you.
如果你想帮你的父亲
If you would help your father,
就力劝你哥哥不要轻举妄动
urge your brother to keep the King's peace.
让他到君临来 向乔佛里宣誓效忠
Tell him to come to King's Landing and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
如果…如果我能见到我父亲 告诉他…
If-- if I could see my father, talk to him about--
孩子 你太让我失望了
You disappoint me, child.
我们已经告诉了你 他的叛国罪行
We have told you of your father's treason.
为什么你还想见一个叛国者呢？
Why would you want to speak to a traitor?
我只是想…
I only meant that--
你们要如何处置他？
What will happen to him?
- 看情况 - 看…看什么情况？
- That depends. - On-- on what?
看你哥哥的表现
On your brother.
还有你
And on you.
谋反？
Treason?
罗柏·史塔克
临冬城公爵长子
这是珊莎写的？
Sansa wrote this?
是你妹妹写的 但明显出于王后的授意
It is your sister's hand, but the Queen's words.
鲁温
临冬城学士
他们召唤你去君临向新国王宣誓效忠
You are summoned to King's Landing to swear fealty to the new king.
乔佛里囚禁了我父亲 现在还要我去亲他的屁股？
Joffrey puts my father in chains, now he wants his ass kissed?
这是王家御旨 大人
This is a royal command, My Lord.
- 如果你要拒绝 - 我不会拒绝
- If you should refuse to obey - I won't refuse.
既然陛下召我去君临
His Grace summons me to King's Landing,
我就照他说的做
I'll go to King's Landing.
但不是独身一人
But not alone.
召集封臣
Call the banners.
全部的封臣 大人？
All of them, My Lord?
他们全都曾宣誓守护我父亲 不是么？
They've all sworn to defend my father, have they not?
是的
They have.
那么现在我们就看看他们的誓言价值几何
Now we see what their words are worth.
很好
Yeah.
你在害怕？
Are you afraid?
我想没错
I must be.
席恩·葛雷乔伊
临冬城公爵养子
很好
Good.
这有什么好的？
Why is that good?
这说明你并不蠢
It means you're not stupid.
你早上就得到了这封信？
You've had this since dawn?
莱莎·徒利
凯特琳·徒利之妹 琼恩·艾林之妻
他送给我的 不是你
He sent it to me, not you.
我给你这个只是出于礼貌
I've only shown it to you as a courtesy.
礼貌？！
A courtesy?!
凯特琳·徒利
临冬城公爵夫人
我丈夫被囚禁
My husband has been taken prisoner.
我儿子准备开战
My son intends to declare war.
罗宾·艾林
琼恩·艾林之子
开战？
A war?
你儿子向兰尼斯特？
Your son against the Lannisters?
你该回到他身边 教教他什么是耐心
You should go to him. Teach him patience.
奈德正遭受牢狱之苦 而你却和我谈耐心？
Ned rots in a dungeon and you speak of patience?
他是你的姐夫啊！
He is your brother by law!
难道家人对你来说什么都不是么？
Does family mean nothing to you?
家人对我来说意味着一切
Family means everything to me.
所以为了罗宾的安危
And I will not risk Robin's life
我绝不会冒险参与你丈夫的又一次战争
to get caught up in another of your husband's wars.
- 我饿了 - 安静 宝贝儿
- I'm hungry. - Hush now, darling.
你刚刚吃过了
You just ate.
所以你不会支持我们了是吗？我理解得没错吧？
You will not support us then? Do I understand you correctly?
- 但我饿了！ - 马上 亲爱的 马上
- But I'm hungry! - Soon, love, soon.
这里一直都欢迎你 姐姐
You're always welcome here, sister.
但你如果想要我把子民从谷地拉进战场
But if you're asking me to send men from the Vale to fight--
我正要向你这样请求
That is what I ask.
去吧 甜心 该洗澡了
Go on, sweet. Time for your bath.
我过会再喂你
I'll feed you after.
如果你为你儿子的安全担心
If you fear for the safety of your son--
我当然担心我儿子的安全！
Of course I fear for the safety of my son!
你是傻子吗？
Are you an idiot?
他们杀了我丈夫
They killed my husband.
你还说他们把你的儿子从窗口扔了下去
You say they shoved your boy from a window.
这些人什么都做得出来
These people will do anything.
正因如此 我们才要阻止他们
And that is why we have to stop them.
艾林谷的骑士将呆在他们的艾林谷
The knights of the Vale will stay in the Vale
保护他们的封君
where they belong, to protect their Lord.
你能闭嘴么？
Will you shut up?
这里到处都有高山部落
There's hill tribes all around here.
如果我要死了
If I'm going to die,
我心里仍旧会唱这么一首
it may as well be with a song in my heart.
我会拿走你的食物然后把你撂下
I should just take your food and leave you here.
恩？那你接下来会怎么做？
Eh? What would you do then?
忍饥挨饿吧 好像只能如此
Starve, most likely.
你不认为我会这么干 是吗？
You don't think I'd do it, do you?
你想要什么 波隆？金子？女人？
What do you want, Bronn? Gold? Women?
还是金头发的女人？
Golden women?
跟着我 你会得到这些的
Stick with me and you'll have them all,
我活着你就荣华富贵 死了你就万事皆休
for as long as I'm around and not for a moment longer.
你很清楚这一点
But you knew that.
这就是你勇敢地拿起武器保护我的原因
That is why you so valiantly took up arms to defend my honor.
算你公道
Fair enough.
但别叫我来卑躬屈膝
But don't go looking for me to bend the knee
每次你拉个屎都要满口“老爷大人”
and "My Lord" you every time you take a shit.
我懒得拍你马屁 你也别当我是朋友
I'm not your toady and I'm not your friend.
尽管如此 我仍会把你的友情视为珍宝
Though I would treasure your friendship,
我主要是对你杀人的本领感兴趣
I'm mainly interested in your facility with murder.
还有 要是哪天有人引诱你出卖我
And if the day ever comes when you're tempted to sell me out,
请你记住
remember this:
提利昂·兰尼斯特
王后幼弟 "小恶魔"
不管对方出价多少 我都出得比他更高
Whatever their price, I'll beat it.
我很爱惜我这条命
I like living.
提利昂
Tyrion.
波隆
佣兵
提利昂
Tyrion.
来啊 诸位 一起烤烤火
Come, share our fire.
欢迎各位前来品尝羊肉
Help yourselves to our goat.
当你升天见到你的神后 告诉他们
When you meet your Gods, you tell them
夏嘎
石鸦部的首领
送你上天的
Shagga Son of Dolf
是石鸦部的多夫之子夏嘎
of the Stone Crows sent you.
我是兰尼斯特部的泰温之子提利昂
I am Tyrion son of Tywin of Clan Lannister.
你想怎么个死法？泰温之子提利昂
How would you like to die, Tyrion son of Tywin?
我想活到八十岁 喝饱一肚子酒
In my own bed, at the age of 80
找个姑娘含着我的鸡巴 这才死在自己的暖床上
with a bellyful of wine and a girl's mouth around my cock.
抓了半人
Take the half man.
我们可以让他跳舞逗孩子开心 杀了另外一个家伙
He can dance for the children. Kill the other one.
别 别 别！
No no no no no!
我…我的家族既有钱又有势
My-- my House is rich and powerful.
只要你们能保护我们平安出山
If you see us through these mountains,
我老爸赏你们的金子会多到可以拿来洗澡
my father will shower you with gold.
半人的承诺对我们来说没用
We have no use for a half man's promises.
我也许只是半个人 但至少我有勇气面对敌人
Half a man maybe, but at least I have the courage to face my enemies.
石鸦部呢？
What do the Stone Crows do?
等峡谷骑士来了
Hide behind rocks and shiver
你们还不是只敢躲在石头后面 害怕得发抖？
when the knights of the Vale ride by?
你偷到的最好的货色就这样？
Are those the best weapons you could steal?
杀羊或许可以
Good enough for killing sheep,
只要那羊乖乖认命让你们杀
if the sheep don't fight back.
兰尼斯特的铁匠拉出的屎都比这高级
Lannister smiths shit better steel.
你认为用你们的小玩意儿就能争取到我们？
You think you can win us over with your trinkets?
那个小玩意儿比你部族里的任何东西都更值钱
That trinket is worth more than everything your tribe owns.
而如果你帮助我 多夫之子夏嘎
But if you help us, Shagga Son of Dolf,
我给你的远不止这些
I will not give you trinkets.
我会给你这个
I will give you this.
“这个”是什么
What is "this"?
整个艾林谷
The Vale of Arryn.
峡谷公爵总是在侮辱山脉氏族
The Lords of the Vale have always spat upon the hill tribes.
峡谷公爵也想让我死
The Lords of the Vale want me dead.
我认为是时候让谷地换个新老爷了
I believe it is time for new Lords of the Vale.
看啊 这儿有个稀罕货
Now there's a rare sight--
不仅是个杂种 还是叛徒的杂种
not only a bastard, but a traitor's bastard.
- 琼恩 不要！ - 琼恩 住手 放下武器！
- Jon, no! - Jon, stop, put it down!
血统说明了一切
Blood will always tell.
你会为此付出代价的 杂种
You'll hang for this, bastard.
艾里沙·索恩
黑城堡的守夜人教头
葛兰
守夜人的游骑兵
我告诉过你别做傻事
I told you not to do anything stupid.
你被关禁闭了 去吧
You're confined to quarters. Go.
白灵 出什么事了？
Ghost, what's wrong?
外面有什么东西吗？
Is something out there?
总司令？
Commander?
别动
Stay.
嗨？
Hello?
谁？
Who's there?
总司令大人？
Lord Commander?
雪诺？
Snow?
总司令！
Commander!
快跑 快点！
Move move!
他们都干了些什么？
What did they do?
Haesh rakhi davrae zafraan.
羊人会是很好的奴隶
Lamb men make good salves.
Khal Drogo vazhoe mora azzafrokea,
卓戈卡奥会将他们作为礼物赠予奴隶主
Khal Drogo will make a gift of them to the slavers,
majin azzafroki vazhi kishaan ma hoshor
而奴隶主会回赠我们金子
and the slavers will give us gold
ma tasokh ma tawakof.
以及丝绸和钢铁
and silk and steel.
我以为多斯拉克人并不信任金钱
I thought the Dothraki didn't believe in money.
金子可以雇船 公主殿下
Gold to hire ships, Princess,
去维斯特洛的船
ships to sail to Westeros.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
卡丽熙
乔拉 叫他们住手
Jorah, make them stop.
- 卡丽熙？ - 你听到了我在说什么
- Khaleesi? - You heard me.
那些人为了卡奥流血卖命 如今他们有权取得应有的奖赏
These men have shed blood for their Khal. Now they claim their rewards.
Me vafik, zhey khaleesi.
她只不过是个羊女 卡丽熙
She's a lamb girl, Khaleesi.
Dothraki chomoe mae.
能被战士们骑 是她的荣誉
The riders do her honor.
Hash athlaqar mae zireyesee khaleesies hash anha
如果她的喊叫声吵到了卡丽熙
If her wailing offends the Khaleesi,
afichak shafkea lekh moon.
我可以为您割下她的舌头
I will bring you her tongue.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
杰奥·莫尔蒙之子
公主殿下 您心怀仁慈
Princess, you have a gentle heart,
但这是他们的传统
but this is how it's always been.
我想我并不仁慈 爵士
I do not have a gentle heart, Ser.
Ti mae k'asi, che Khal Drogo anesa valzerikh.
照我说的做 否则卓戈卡奥唯你们是问
Do as I command or Khal Drogo will know the reason why.
过来
Come.
你打算怎么处置她们
What do you want done with them?
把她带到我这来 把那些女人带去那边吧
Bring her to me. And those women there.
弥丽·马兹·笃尔
神庙女祭司
你没法把她们统统收归己有 公主
You cannot claim them all, Princess.
我可以
I can,
而且我正有此意
and I will.
Me Fati!
这是对我的侮辱！
It's an insult!
Khaleesi vazha anhaan qorasokh anni,
卡丽熙必须把我的战利品还回来
Khaleesi will give me my prize
ch'anha afichak mae m'arakhoon anni!
否则我就亲自用弯刀抢回来
or I will take it with my arakh.
Me vastoe hatif anni;
她会过来告诉我发生了什么
She will speak before me;
ahhazaan yer nemo vacchaki.
在此之前你都给我闭上嘴
until then you will keep yourself quite.
Zhey jalan atthirari anni,
我生命中的月亮
Moon of my life,
Mago asta meshafka fich qorasokh mae,
马戈说你夺走了他的战利品
Mago says you have taken his spoils,
ohara haeshi rakhi fin qoraso me asaja mae.
一个应该让他骑的羊人之女
a daughter of the lamb man who was his to mount.
Asti anhaan hash jini jila.
告诉我实话
Tell me the truth of this.
Mago asta k'athjilari, zhey shekh ma shieraki anni.
马戈说的没错 我的日和星
Mago speaks the truth, my sun and stars.
卓戈 卡奥
多斯拉克部族首领
Anha ray qoraso san ohari asshekh
我今天认养了许多女儿
I have claimed many daughters this day
majin mori nem vos osaji.
所以任何人都不许骑她们
so they cannot be mounted.
Jini athvilajerar.
这是战争之道
This is the way of war.
Jin chiorisi zafra ajjin,
眼下这些女人都是奴隶
These women are slaves
majin kisha ataki morea ven me vallayafa kisha.
随我们高兴而处置
now to do with as we please.
Anha nem allayafak vassandik mora.
那我高兴让她们平安
It pleases me to keep them safe.
Hash dothraki shafki'th saji mora hash mori jif kemoe ma moroa.
若你的战士们想骑她们 就先把她们收做妻子
If your riders would mount them, let them take them as wives.
Hash hrazef gova vaf?
马怎么能和羊配对？
Does the horse mate with the lamb?
Zhavvorsa vadakhera ma hrazef ma vaf akkate.
对龙而言马和羊一样是食物
The dragon feeds on horse and lamb alike.
Yer ifak.
你是个外来者
You're a foreigner.
Yer assoo anna vosecchi.
你不能命令我
You do not command me.
Anha Khaleesi. Anha assok yera sekosshi.
我是卡丽熙 当然能命令你
I am Khaleesi. I do command you.
Tihi kifinosi me ivezhofoe?
看到她变得多凶猛了吗？
See how fierce she grows?
Hazak rizh anni mra me: Vezh fini Asaja Rhaesheseres,
这都是因为我的儿子 骑着世界的骏马
That's my son inside her, the stallion that will mount the world,
fini nirra mae vorsasoon mae.
在她体内 让她充满火焰
filling her with his fire.
Anha acharak vos ale.
我不想再听到关于此事的争吵了
I will hear no more.
Mago, Ezas eshna gech ahilee.
马戈 去找别的羊女骑
Mago, find somewhere else to stick your cock.
Khal fines assoe mezhah jahakmeni vos khal.
一个听命于外人的卡奥就不算是卡奥了
A Khal who takes orders from a foreign whore is no Khal.
Ohos!
住手
Be Still.
Os!
别动
Don't move.
马戈
血盟卫
Anha vazhok khadoes yeroon virsalat.
我不会让他们烧掉你的尸体
I will not have you body burned.
Anha ochomok yeraan kijinosi.
我不会给你那个荣誉
I will not give you that honor.
Inte vadakhie
甲虫会吞吃你的眼睛
The beetles will feed on your eyes.
tihoa ma khewo afilki vi gadimaan.
蠕虫将在你的肺里爬行
The worms will crawl through your lungs.
Eyel varthasoe she ilekaan rikhoya arrekaan
雨水会打落在你腐烂的皮肤上
The rain will fall on your rotting skin
vekha vosi yeroon vosma tolorro!
直到只剩骸骨残余
until nothing is left of you but bones.
Atte yer eth addrivi anna.
但你得先杀得了我
First you have to kill me.
Jin anha ray et.
你已经死了
I already have.
Shekh ma shieraki anni zisa.
我的日和星受伤了
My sun and stars is hurt.
Me zisosh,
擦伤而已
A scratch,
zhey jalan atthirari anni.
我生命中的月亮
moon of my life.
Finne koalaki?
医者在哪儿？
Where are the healers.
Jini osto afisi.
不过是被苍蝇叮了一口
This is the bite of a fly.
Anha laz rhelak dothrakes vezhvena ha zisoshaan mae.
我可以为伟大的骑马战士处理伤口
I can help the great rider with his cut.
哈戈
血盟卫
Khal zigeree vo rhellay ha zafroon fini govi oqet.
卡奥不需要跟羊交配的奴隶来帮忙
The Khal needs no help from slaves who lie with sheep.
Me anni. Me vastoe.
她是我的人 让她说下去
She's mine. Let her speak.
谢谢你 银夫人
Thank you, silver lady.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我名为弥丽·马兹·笃尔 是这座神庙的女祭司
I am named Mirri Maz Duur. I was the godswife of this temple.
Maegi.
巫魔女
Witch.
我的母亲也曾是这里的女祭司
My mother was godswife here before me.
她教我如何调制圣烟和圣膏
She taught me how to make healing smokes and ointments.
在牧神治下 万物皆是平等 这是我们的信仰
All men are of one flock, so my people believe.
至高牧神派我下凡医治他的…
The Great Shepherd sent me to Earth to heal his--
Ase sekke. Ase maegi izzi char.
她说的太多了 听她说话会毒坏耳朵
Too many words. The witch's words poison the ears.
羊羔还是狮子
Lamb or lion,
他的伤口需要清洗包扎
his wound must be washed and sewn
否则会溃烂
or it will fester.
Azhas maan affisat zis yeri, shekh ma shieraki anni.
让她清理你的伤口吧 我的日和星
Let her clean your wound my sun and stars.
Me azzisa anna jin tihat meyer qiyae.
看到你受伤 我也很痛苦
It makes me hurt to see you bleed.
我在死人堆里打滚已经三十多年了
For 30 years I've been making corpses
小子
out of men, boy.
琼恩·安柏
史塔克家族的封臣 "大琼恩"
我才是为你统帅先锋的最佳人选
I'm the man you want leading the vanguard.
我将任命盖伯特·葛洛佛来统帅先锋
Galbart Glover will lead the van.
要想安柏家的人跟在葛洛佛后面
The bloody Wall will melt
除非那该死的长城融掉
before an Umber marches behind a Glover.
我要统领先锋
I will lead the van
否则我就立刻带着我的人
or I will take my men
班师回家
and march them home.
欢迎您这么做 安柏伯爵
You are welcome to do so, Lord Umber.
等收拾掉兰尼斯特之后
And when I am done with the Lannisters
我们会立刻回师北方
I will march back north,
把你从你家的城堡里抓出来
root you out of your keep
当成背誓者吊死
and hang you for an oathbreaker.
背誓者 是吗？
Oathbreaker, is it?!
别以为我会坐在这里任你侮辱
I'll not sit here and swallow insults
你这撒尿都是草绿色的小鬼
from a boy so green he pisses grass.
我父亲大人曾经教导我 在宣誓效忠的封君面前拔剑
My Lord father taught me it was death to bare steel
乃是死罪
against your liege lord.
但也许大琼恩只是想为我切肉罢了
But doubtless the Great jon only meant to cut my meat for me.
你的肉
Your meat
还真他妈的硬
is bloody tough.
布兰·史塔克
临冬城公爵次子
- 怎么回事？发生什么了？ - 嘘 没事
- What is it? What's happened? - Shh, it's all right.
- 你要去哪儿？ - 去南方 为了救父亲
- Where are you going? - South. For father.
但现在是午夜啊
But it's the middle of the night.
兰尼斯特的探子无处不在
The Lannisters have spies everywhere.
我不想让他们知道我们的动向
I don't want them to know we're coming.
他们比我们人多
They have more men than we do.
是啊 的确
Aye, they do.
我不能跟你一起去吗？
Can't I come with you?
我现在可以骑马了 你看过我骑马的样子
I can ride now. You've seen me riding.
而且我绝不会给你添麻烦 我…
And I won't get in the way, I--
临冬城中不能没有史塔克
There must always be a Stark at Winterfell.
在我回来以前 那便是你的责任
Until I return that will be you.
我们离开的这段时间里 你不能踏出城墙半步 听懂了吗？
You are not to leave the castle walls while we are gone. Do you understand?
听从鲁温师傅的意见 照顾好你的小弟弟
Listen to Maester Luwin. Look after your little brother.
我会的
I will.
只要有机会我就写信
I'll send letters whenever I can,
但如果你失去了我的消息
but if you don't hear from me,
也不要害怕
don't be scared.
等我回来
Until I return.
你在那儿藏了多久了？
How long have you been hiding out there?
罗柏肯定在四处找你道别呢
Robb will be looking for you to say goodbye.
瑞肯·史塔克
临冬城公爵幼子
他们全都走了
They've all gone away.
他们很快就会回家 罗柏会救出父亲
They'll be back soon. Robb will free father
然后他们会和母亲一起回家
and they'll come back with mother.
不 他们不会的
No, they won't.
拜托 请照看罗柏
Please watch over Robb.
以及临冬城的所有人
And watch over all the other men from Winterfell.
席恩也算吧 我想
And Theon too, I suppose.
你听到他们的回答了吗 小子？
You hear them, boy?
旧神正在回答你呢
The Old Gods are answering you.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
他们也是我的神
They're my Gods too.
在长城之外 他们是唯一的真神
Beyond the Wall, they're the only Gods.
即便是奴隶也有资格祈祷
Even slaves are allowed to pray.
你不是奴隶
You're not a slave.
呃 这要怪你朋友当时用匕首抵着我的喉咙
Well, your friend did put a knife to my throat.
我这不是发牢骚 小主人
I'm not complaining, little lord,
只是在陈述事实
just telling truths.
你刚才说能听到旧神说话 那是什么意思？
What did you mean about hearing the Gods?
你向他们祈求
You asked them,
而他们正在回答
they're answering you.
欧莎
女野人
竖起耳朵
Open your ears.
不过是风声
It's only the wind.
你以为这风是谁送来的啊？
Who do you think sends the wind
当然是天上诸神啊
if not the Gods?
他们看到了你 小子
They see you, boy.
也听到了你说的话
They hear you.
你哥哥要去的地方 他们无法帮他
Your brother will get no help from them where he's going.
旧神在南方没有力量
The Old Gods have no power in the South.
那儿的鱼梁木早在很多年前就被砍伐一空
The weirwoods there were all cut down a long time ago.
没有眼睛 他们该如何去看呢？
How can they watch when they have no eyes?
啊 他可真是个大块头
Well, there's a big man.
阿多
临冬城的马童 老奶妈的曾孙
他要是没有巨人血统 我肯定就是女王了
He has giants' blood in him or I'm the Queen.
阿多 回去穿上衣服
Go back and find your clothes, Hodor.
去穿衣服
Go dress.
阿多
Hodor.
长城之外真的有巨人吗？
Are there really giants beyond the Wall?
巨人 以及比巨人更可怕的东西
Giants and worse than giants.
我试过告诉你哥哥
I tried telling your brother,
他走错了方向
he's marching the wrong way.
他的军队应该去北方的 小子
All these swords, they should be going north, boy.
北方 不是南方！
North, not south!
冷风已然吹起
The cold winds are rising.
他们被异鬼触碰过
They were touched by White Walkers.
雷斯特
守夜人的游骑兵
所以才能返回长城
That's why they came back.
所以变成了蓝眼睛
That's why their eyes turned blue.
唯有火焰能够阻挡他们
Only fire will stop them.
你怎么知道这些的？
How do you know that?
我从一本书中读到的
I read about it in a book--
伊蒙师傅藏书室中的一本非常非常古老的书
a very old book in Maester Aemon's library.
那书里还说了什么？
What else did the book say?
异鬼
The White Walkers
在寒冰之下沉睡数千年
sleep beneath the ice for thousands of years.
等他们醒来后
And when they wake up--
等他们醒来后 就怎么了？
And when they wake up, what?
派普尔
守夜人 亦称“派普”
我只希望绝境长城足够高
I hope the Wall is high enough.
夏雪啊 夫人
Summer snows, My Lady.
罗柏将整个北境都带来了
Robb's brought the North with him.
河间地的领主正在
The river lords are falling back
詹姆·兰尼斯特的追击之下节节败退
with Jaime Lannister at their heels.
而泰温公爵正带着另一支兰尼斯特军队从南方杀来
And Lord Tywin is bringing around a second Lannister army from the south.
我们的斥候确定 那支军队比弑君者麾下的还要庞大
Our scouts confirm it's even larger than the Kingslayer's.
管他是一支军队还是两支 古代的北境之王
One army or two, the Kings in the North
曾击退过十倍于此的强敌
threw back hosts 10 times as large.
母亲！
Mother!
罗德利克·凯索
临冬城教头
你看上去很好
You look well.
凯特林夫人 在这个动乱时刻 见到您真是令人宽心
Lady Catelyn, you're a welcome sight in these troubled times.
夫人 没想到会在这里见到您
We had not thought to meet you here, My Lady.
我也没想到会来这里
I had not thought to be here.
我希望能和儿子单独谈谈
I would speak with my son alone.
相信诸位大人必会谅解
I know you will forgive me, My Lords.
你们听到她说的了！快走！
You heard her! Move your asses!
来吧 出去
Come on, out.
还有你 葛雷乔伊 你他妈聋了吗？
You too, Greyjoy. Are you bloody deaf?
别害怕 夫人
Have no fear, My Lady.
咱们过不了多久就会把剑捅进泰温·兰尼斯特的屁眼
We'll shove our swords up Tywin Lannister's bunghole
然后一路杀进红堡 把奈德救出来
and then it's on to the Red Keep to free Ned.
- 你这老混蛋 罗德利克 - 琼恩
- You old devil, Rodrik. - Jon.
你怎么变瘦了？
You're not wasting away, are you?
我仍然记得你来到世上的那天
I remember the day you came into this world
红着脸 呱呱坠地
red-faced and squalling.
如今却发觉你正率领部下投入战场
And now I find you leading a host to war.
- 除了我没别人了 - 没别人？
- There was no one else. - No one?
我刚刚见到的那些人是谁？
Who were those men I saw here?
- 他们都不是史塔克 - 可他们全都阅历丰富 身经百战
- None of them are Starks. - All of them are seasoned in battle.
如果你认为能把我送回临冬城
If you think you can send me back to Winterfell--
噢 我的确该那么做
Oh, would that I could.
这里…
There was...
有封信
a letter.
珊莎写的
From Sansa.
你是指“王后写的”吧
From the Queen, you mean.
- 这里面没有提到艾莉亚 - 没有
- There's no mention of Arya. - No.
你带来了多少人？
How many men do you have?
一万八千人
18,000.
如果我前往君临 然后对乔佛里宣誓效忠
If I go to King's Landing and bend my knee to Joffrey--
便永远不可能脱身 不能去
You would never be allowed to leave. No.
我们最大的希望 或者说唯一的希望
Our best hope-- our only hope--
便是你能在战场上击败对手
is that you can defeat them in the field.
如果我失败了呢？
And if I lose?
你知道疯王死后 坦格利安家
Do you know what happened to the Targaryen children
- 那些孩子们的下场吗？ - 他们在睡梦中惨遭杀害
- when the Mad King fell? - They were butchered in their sleep.
是泰温·兰尼斯特下的命令
On the orders of Tywin Lannister.
虽然过了这么多年 他也绝对不会变得心慈手软
And the years have not made him kinder.
如果你失败了
If you lose,
你的父亲会死
your father dies,
你的妹妹们会死
your sisters die,
我们 都会死
we die.
这样一来倒是简单了许多
Well, that makes it simple then.
希望如此吧
I suppose it does.
从这里开始 最好只让我和波隆两个人下去
From here it might be best if Bronn and I continue alone.
对泰温之子提利昂来说最好
Best for Tyrion son of Tywin.
对我可一点都不好
Not best for me.
如果半人胆敢耍我们
If the half man betrays us,
多夫之子夏嘎就要剁掉他的命根子…
Shagga Son of Dolf will cut off his manhood--
拿去喂山羊 我知道
And feed it to the goats, yes.
算啦
All right then.
该去见我父亲了
Time to meet my father.
- 提利昂 - 叔叔
- Tyrion. - Uncle.
父亲
Father.
看来关于你已死的传言不攻自破了
The rumors of your demise were unfounded.
抱歉让您失望了
Sorry to disappoint you.
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 西境守护 国王外祖父
这些跟在你身边的…
And who are these...
贵客们 是些什么人？
companions of yours?
这位是多夫之子夏嘎
This is Shagga, son of Dolf,
石鸦部的酋长
Chieftain of the Stone Crows.
提魅之子提魅 灼人部的头领
Timett Son of Timett, ruler of the Burned Men.
这位美少女是齐克之女齐拉
This fair maid is Chella daughter of Cheyk,
她是黑耳部的首领
leader of the Black Ears.
这位是波隆 他的父亲…
And here we have Bronn son of...
你不会认识他的
You wouldn't know him.
容我为各位介绍家父
May I present my lord father,
凯岩城公爵暨西境守护
Tywin son of Tytos of House Lannister,
兰尼斯特家族的泰陀斯之子泰温
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the West?
感谢您为了我而开战
Kind of you to go to war for me.
事关家族荣誉
You left us no choice.
你让我别无选择
The honor of the House was at stake.
换成你哥哥 他绝不会如此轻易屈服于女人之手
Your brother would never have submitted to capture so meekly.
詹姆和我有很多不同
We have our differences, Jaime and I.
他更有勇气 我更加帅气
He's braver. I'm better looking.
他为自己争得满身的荣耀
He's been covering himself in glory.
詹姆在金牙城击溃了河间诸侯
Jaime smashed the river lords at the Golden Tooth,
凯冯·兰尼斯特
泰温·兰尼斯特之弟
现在已经包围了奔流城 凯特琳·史塔克的娘家
and now lays siege to Riverrun, Catelyn Stark's homeland.
史塔克家的人呢？艾德大人呢？
And the Starks? Lord Eddard?
他是我们的人质 在地牢里可无法统领军队
Is our hostage. He will lead no armies from his dungeon cell.
我的好姐姐究竟是怎么说服了劳勃国王
How did my sweet sister persuade the King
让他同意囚禁自己亲爱的好朋友奈德？
to imprison his dear friend Ned?
劳勃·拜拉席恩已经死了 如今在君临执政的是乔佛里
Robert Baratheon is dead. Joffrey rules in King's Landing.
你是说 我姐姐执政
My sister rules, you mean.
史塔克的儿子已经召集封臣
Stark's son has called his banners.
- 他正率领大军南下 - 一个毛头小子
- He moves south with a strong host. - A green boy.
一旦品尝过战争的滋味
One taste of battle and he'll run
就会夹着尾巴逃回临冬城
back to Winterfell with his tail between his legs.
有可能
Maybe.
不过这小子生性好斗
Though the boy does have a certain belligerence.
你会喜欢他的
You'd like him.
既然说到了打仗
While we're on the subject of war,
我曾对这几位朋友许下承诺
I made promises to my friends here
而且兰尼斯特有债必偿
and a Lannister always pays his debts.
我们需要三千顶头盔和三千套锁甲
We shall require 3,000 helms and shields,
还有剑 长枪
plus swords, pikes,
颈甲 钉头锤
gorgets, maces--
启禀大人
If it please My Lord,
亚当爵士命我前来报告
Ser Addam bids me report
北方人已经穿过了颈泽
that the Northmen have crossed the Neck.
狼入狮口
The wolf rushes into the lion's jaws.
好极了 凯冯 吩咐鼓手敲集合令
So be it. Kevan, command the drummers beat assembly.
并派人传话通知詹姆 我要即刻进军 与罗柏·史塔克决战
And send word to Jaime that I am moving against Robb Stark.
遵命 大人
At once, My Lord.
据说高山部落的男子是勇猛无惧的战士
It is said that the men of the mountain clans are great warriors.
与我一同出兵抗敌
Ride with me against my enemies
我保证你们能得到我儿子承诺的一切 甚至更多
and you shall have all my son promised you and more.
那么半人必须跟我们在一起
Only if the half man fights with us.
在我们拿到他答应的武器之前
Until we hold the steel he pledged us,
小狮子的命是我们的
the little lion's life is ours.
据斥候来报 泰温公爵已经挥师北进
The scouts report Lord Tywin moves north.
我们必须把他引到松软的地层上去
We need to get him on broken ground,
那样不利于兰尼斯特的骑兵作战
put his knights at a disadvantage.
不 我们要包围他
No, we need to get around him
然后击破詹姆·兰尼斯特的包围圈
and break Jaime Lannister's siege of Riverrun.
这样做 河间诸侯就会加入我们
Do that and the river lords will join us.
不论怎样做我们都必须过河
To do either we need to cross the river
唯一的渡口在孪河城
and the only crossing is at the Twins.
佛雷侯爵把守着渡口
Lord Frey controls that bridge.
他是你父亲的封臣
Your father's bannerman.
我父亲称他“迟到的佛雷侯爵”
"The late Lord Frey" my father calls him.
当年在三叉戟河 直到战争结束他才出现
At the Trident, he didn't appear until the battle was done.
有些人对待誓言比别人严肃得多
Some men takes their oaths more seriously than others.
罗柏说得对 我们需要这座桥
Robb's right. We need that bridge.
那么接下来怎么做？
So what's it going to be?
我们是攻击詹姆还是迎击泰温公爵？
Do we move against Jaime or Lord Tywin?
恕我打扰 大人们
Your pardon, my lords.
我们抓住了一名兰尼斯特斥候
We've captured a Lannister scout.
别担心 小子 他不可能活着走出去
Don't worry, lad. He won't be leaving this tent with his head.
你们在哪里抓到他的？
Where did you find him?
营地附近的灌木丛
In the brush above the encampment.
他好像在清点什么
He looked to be counting.
你数了多少？
How high did you get?
两万 至少两万
20,000. Maybe more.
你没必要亲自行刑
You don't have to do this yourself.
令尊大人会理解
Your father would understand--
我父亲总是心怀仁慈 我们应当给他一个机会
My father understands mercy, when there is room for it.
他还理解荣誉
And he understands honor...
以及勇气
and courage.
放了他
Let him go.
罗柏
Robb.
请知会泰温 凛冬已为他而至
Tell Lord Tywin Winter is coming for him.
两万北方战士南下 来看他能不能拉出黄金屎
20,000 northerners marching south to find out if he really does shit gold.
遵命 大人
Yes, My Lord.
多谢 大人
Thank you, My Lord.
你疯了吗 小子？放他走？
Are you touched, boy?! Letting him go?
你敢再叫我一次小子
You call me boy again.
叫啊
Go on.
陛下有令
It is also the wish of His Grace
擢升尽忠职守的君临都城守备队队长
that his loyal servant Janos Slynt,
- 杰诺斯·史林特… - 艾伦爵士
- Commander of the City Watch... - Ser Aron.
…为贵族行列…
...Be at once raised to the rank of Lord...
- 盖尔斯伯爵 - 并赐予其历史悠久的赫伦堡
- Lord Gyles. - And granted the ancient seat of Harrenhal,
其子嗣将世代承袭此等荣耀
and that his sons and grandsons shall hold this honor after him
万世不辍
until the end of time.
乔佛里·拜拉席恩
铁王座上的王
杰诺斯·史林特
都城守备队队长
为取代叛徒艾德·史塔克
In the place of the traitor Eddard Stark,
派席尔
大学士
遵照国王陛下的意愿
it is the wish of His Grace that Tywin Lannister,
由凯岩城公爵暨西境守护泰温·兰尼斯特
Lord of Casterly Rock and Warden of the West,
接任首相一职
be appointed Hand of the King.
最后
Lastly,
值此密谋四起 动乱不堪的危殆之际
in these times of treason and turmoil,
吾等御前会议之重臣认为
it is the view of the Council
培提尔·贝里席
财政大臣 “小指头”
乔佛里国王
that the life and safety
之生命安危
of King Joffrey
实乃首要之急
be of paramount importance.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥爵士听命
Ser Barristan Selmy.
陛下 微臣听候您的差遣
Your Grace, I am yours to command.
请起 巴利斯坦爵士
Rise, Ser Barristan.
您可以卸下头盔
You may remove your helm.
长久以来您为国效命 尽忠职守
You have served the Realm long and faithfully.
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
御林铁卫队长
七大王国中男女老少皆对您心怀感激
Every man and woman in the Seven Kingdoms owes you thanks.
然而现在 恐怕您是时候解甲归田
But it is time to put aside your armor and your sword.
告老还乡
It is time to rest and look back with pride
回顾您一生无数的荣耀
on your many years of service.
陛下 御林铁卫乃宣誓效命的兄弟
Your Grace, the Kingsguard is a sworn brotherhood.
立下誓言 即为终身
Our vows are taken for life.
惟死方能解除我等神圣使命
Only death relieves us of our sacred trust.
巴利斯坦爵士 敢问是谁的死？是你还是你的国王？
Whose death, Ser Barristan? Yours or your King's?
你保护不了我父亲
You let my father die.
你年纪太大 谁都保护不了
You're too old to protect anybody.
- 陛下… - 御前会议已经决定
- Your Grace-- - The Council has determined
由詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士接任你的职务
that Ser Jaime Lannister will take your place
担任御林铁卫队长
as Lord Commander of the Kingsguard.
就是那个以他誓言守护的国王
The man who profaned his blade
的鲜血来玷污自己宝剑的虚伪骑士么！
with the blood of the King he had sworn to defend!
爵士 请注意您的措辞
Careful, Ser.
对于您过去的贡献
We have nothing but gratitude
我们非常感激 好爵士
for your long service, good Ser.
您被赐予海边一块肥沃的封地
You shall be given a stout keep beside the sea,
以及足够满足您需要的仆人
with servants to look after your every need.
给我一个等死的地方
A hall to die in
和为我送终的人
and men to bury me.
我既生为骑士
I am a knight.
也要死得像个骑士
I shall die a knight.
显然 是个没穿衣服的骑士
A naked knight, apparently.
即便现在 我依旧可以像切乳酪一样把你们五个通通砍倒
Even now I could cut through the five of you like carving a cake!
小鬼 拿去罢！
Here, boy!
熔了这把剑 让王座上再多一把
Melt it down and add it to the others.
陛下倾听在场诸位的请愿
If any man in this hall has other matters
有事禀报
to set before His Grace, let him speak now
无事退朝
or go forth and hold his silence.
国王陛下
Your Grace.
小姐 请您上前来
Come forward, My Lady.
史塔克家族的珊莎小姐
The Lady Sansa of House Stark.
珊莎 你有事禀报国王陛下和御前会议？
Do you have some business for the King and the Council, Sansa?
是的
I do.
陛下开恩 我要为家父
As it please Your Grace, I ask mercy for my father,
亦即前首相艾德·史塔克公爵请愿
Lord Eddard Stark, who was Hand of the King.
叛国大罪好似带毒的野草
Treason is a noxious weed.
- 必须连根拔除 斩尽… - 让她说吧
- It should be torn out, root-- - Let her speak.
我要听听她的话
I want to hear what she says.
感谢您 陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
令尊所犯之罪行 你可否认？
Do you deny your father's crime?
诸位大人 我不否认 我很清楚他必须接受制裁
No, My Lords. I know he must be punished.
我要求的只是网开一面
All I ask is mercy.
家父必定已对其所作所为懊悔不已
I know My Lord father must regret what he did.
他是劳勃国王生前密友 敬他爱他
He was King Robert's friend and he loved him.
在座各位都明白他对国王的一片真心
You all know he loved him.
国王开口之前 他甚至从未动过成为首相的念头
He never wanted to be Hand until the King asked him.
他必定是被蓝礼公爵 史坦尼斯公爵
They must have lied to him-- Lord Renly or Lord Stannis
或某些人蛊惑的 他一定是被蛊惑的！
or somebody. They must have lied!
他说我不是国王
He said I wasn't the King.
他为什么要那样说？
Why did he say that?
他重伤在身
He was badly hurt.
派席尔大学士给他服用了罂粟花奶
Maester Pycelle was giving him milk of the poppy.
让他神志不清 否则他是绝不会这样说的
He wasn't himself. Otherwise he never would have said it.
这是孩子对父亲的信心所致… 多么单纯而天真
A child's faith... Such sweet innocence.
可是人们不是常说
And yet they say wisdom oft comes
智慧往往来自孩子口中么
from the mouths of babes.
但叛国就是叛国！
Treason is treason!
你还有什么要说的吗？
Anything else?
如果您对我还有些许眷恋之心
If you still have any affection in your heart for me,
就请以仁慈之心手下留情吧 陛下
please do me this kindness, Your Grace.
你的一番肺腑之言感动了我
Your sweet words have moved me.
但你父亲必须俯首认罪
But your father has to confess.
他必须承认我是他的国王
He has to confess and say that I'm the King...
不然我无法宽恕他
Or there'll be no mercy for him.
他会的
He will.
龙堡字幕组 & 衣柜字幕组 出品